Welcome again to User Experience
UX36. And this is the assignment
overview. So it's still
logistical, but I want to tell
you about the assignments, why
they were created, and really,
why they were put together and
what they're there to test. So
there's two types of assignments
that we'll be working with.
There's the formative
assignment, which is for
feedback only. So you don't have
to do it. It's optional. If you
don't want to do it, you don't
need to, but you must do it
within the allocated time. We
can't do it afterwards because
we can't reallocate the TA
resources to help with the
marking and the feedback to you.
So, you must if you want to do
it, you must do it within the
first period of time that we
talked about in the lectures in
the video lectures. After that,
there's two summative
assignments. So after you've had
your feedback, you can do the
two summative assignments which
contribute to the overall mark,
they're 15% each. So it's
reasonable to get those under
your belts before you go into
the main tests, if you like in
the main part of the work now
the assignments themselves, you
should, you should try and do
them. I think trying to get them
all done by the end of reading
week, okay, so you'll get a good
idea of what you need to do and
how you need to approach them by
coming to the discussion
lectures and the the kind of the
consolidation lectures and you
should be able to do them, you
know, probably within the first
six to seven weeks, okay? So try
and get those out of the way if
you possibly can and if you feel
uncomfortable with it, that's
what then that's what they're
meant to be there for. Now, the
first one is the formative
assignment, discussion topic.
This is understanding and
scoping and defining the user
experience. And the reason why
this was created this paper was
selected is because it really
shows that in 2009, you'll find
out that even today, nobody
really knows what UX is. So the
good point is, if you don't know
what it is, I don't know what it
is we're making our own
definitions. The good thing is
that nobody's wrong. But we do
need to define the terms when
we're in discussions with other
people of what we actually think
this is, this is about. So this
survey approaches is a way of
kind of understanding what UX
is. And so what happened was
that Effie Law, who is the the,
the main author of this, went to
the CHI conference, which is a
major conference for Computer
Human Interaction, and she
wanted to ask the people who
came there what they thought it
was, or at least there was
questionnaire that they were
able to rank what, with
agreement or disagreement rank,
what they thought it was really
about on a number of different
metrics and a number of
different axis. And so I think
it's important for us to kind of
read through this to understand
what the, what the outcomes were
and also what the negative
points were, really what were
the failings of this survey
approach. And we do use this as
a critically important part part
of the course. So let's not get
serious, and let's not, you
know, stray too far that this is
a good bit of work. But it's a
good idea for us to chat about
this in the context of this
formative assignment so that you
can kind of pick up what you
need to do so that you'll get
feedback from from this first
The next one is the summative
kind of dry run and assignments,
assignment. So this is the first
but it's optional.
summative assignment and it's
designing the star user
interface. So star user
interfaces were really where all
GUIs began. It's something that
was created out of Xerox PARC wh
ch was an awesome place and sti
l is. But it's an awesome pl
ce where there was a lot of exc
llent work going on through th
60s 70s and 80s. And indeed, th
s is really where where Stev
Jobs took his inspiratio
for the way that the the Mac sh
uld work. This kind of idea of
GUIs and how it all fits togethe
, it was really proved at Xe
ox PARC. And they did this oth
r thing that was really aweso
e, called dogfooding.
hereby they would all use the
tar user interface on all of th
machines in their in Xerox PAR
in their company. So therefore
they proved it by actually usi
g it. So really good, really
good. article here on designing
it and something you should t
ke forward to your user testing
if you possibly can.
The final one is the second is
the second summative assignment.
And this is voice loops as
corporative aids in space
shuttle mission control. The
reason why I selected this one
is because I wanted you guys to
think that UX sounds sort of
nice and fluffy, and it feels
like apps, it feels like iOS, it
feels like Android, it feels
like that kind of thing. But
that's not all it is. UX is
really critically important in
lots of computational situations
and device based situations,
including the computational work
here, on the space shuttle. Also
on computational work, for
things like nuclear power
stations, and how the safety
critical systems such as fly by
wire aircraft can really screw
up. If we don't get the user
experience right in a faithful
way. And when I say user
experience We'll be coming to
this in the future, of course.
But when I say user experience,
I don't just mean, you know,
does it look nice, that's not
the whole point. User Experience
is about the full experience of
the user, how the control flow
works, etc, etc. And even down
in devices to the way things
look and the way things feel,
because we have a tactile sense.
So we want to make sure that
this is an important, you know,
we want to make sure that we
don't get things wrong, even
outside, if you like, of the
software. So, there are a number
of apocryphal stories, you know,
one of them is that you'll see
some images of nuclear power
plants where they have different
beer taps on the top of each of
the control arms. And that's
because the control arms all
look the same. And so they
didn't know they couldn't
differentiate or remember which
one was which. So they put a
beer tap on it, or at least to
be a pull on it with a little
sign on each of them telling
them what they actually did,
after the event after the
nuclear power station has
actually gone into service.
Because the people who are
operating just remember it's too
complex, okay? They all look the
same. That's not what you want
when it comes to something
that's a safety critical as the
controls of a nuclear power
station, right. And you could
also say the same thing about
the the Airbus crash from Brazil
to Paris, whereby, in that
particular accident, you had the
ability for a pilot who was the
copilot to be doing one thing,
ie putting inputs into the
system which were going down,
and for another pilot to be
pulling back so that they would
go up. And of course, these two
things start to interact with
each other. They didn't think
when they designed the system,
that if somebody is already
putting control inputs in one
way that we should at least say
you're the one is barred from
doing it and you have to do
something else, you know, there
has to be a switch that changes
from one to the other. This is
because in typically in
aircraft, you would say, one
pilot would say I have control
and the other person say, yes,
you have control, that'd be a
confirmation, verbal
confirmation. But in situations
which are highly stressful,
where you're not sure what's
happening, those situations
sometimes get missed, okay,
because it's stressful we're
people. So therefore, it's a
good idea to have user
experience designers in there as
well to make sure that the
safety critical systems work.
So how are we going to approach
these? Well, the thing that you
need to think about is it's not
a summary of the paper because I
can read it and get a summary.
What I want is your insights in
the summary. So tell me why the
paper is important. Why should
What should I know and why is it
important. And how does this
paper affect our development?
What insights does the paper
have and How do they affect us?
Can we use the paper to our
advantage? The reason why we ask
these questions is because these
are the kind of things that your
bosses will need you to answer.
They are not UX experts, they
are not research and development
experts like you are going to be
when you get into their company,
they will ask you for a brief on
a paper, they expect you to give
the value added. They can read
the paper, they're smart enough,
they're your boss, right? What
you need to give them is your
expertise which your training
which they haven't had. And you
can only do that by knowing the
area and be able to synthesise
information from other parts of
your knowledge with this
knowledge of the paper that
you're reading into something
that's useful to those to those
people, those technical people,
those business people. So
summarising the paper you need
to do a little bit of that but
that is not all you need to do.
You need to analyse it you need
to evaluate it to to come up
with With some 250 words, so
it's very brief insight. Now,
you don't need to focus on the
whole paper, you can give a
brief overview and then say,
this is the most important thing
for us this bit and ignore the
rest. That's okay. It's not you
can't say everything in 250
words, you need to be able to
understand what is important for
you and for your company and
therefore summarise it to that
to that company, okay, outcome.
So, I think that the important
thing here is that there is a
skill to summarising a paper.
But you I need to add the
analysis in the evaluation. You
need to come up with your 250
words as an industry standard.
But you need to add your own
insight you need to add your own
understanding to this kind of
work so that the people who have
employed you get the value added
of your expertise, what you're
trying to say is, I'm an expert.
And I'm going to tell you about
this particular paper within the
light of my expertise. That's
what we're trying to get to.
It's not enough to just
summarise it. So like I say, in,
you know, you interpret the
paper, you add your insight,
your expertise, in this context,
it's about the UX course. So you
add your expertise in you being
UX, you might draw in bits from
the other courses that you've
taken, that's also perfectly
acceptable to make those links
and synthesise that information
into this particular work. Okay.
It's difficult to not just
produce a summary so I suggest
you get one of your friends to
read over it, see whether they
think it's a summary or see
whether they think there's some
value added in there as well.
Okay. Think to yourself, could
anybody have just read this
paper and then summarise it? Is
my 250 words could anybody have
written them that read the paper
and write my 250 words. If
that's true, your 250 words
aren't correct. If it isn't true
if you if you actually think so
far, no, actually, there's lots
of different bits that I've
pulled from different areas in
it. That's what we want. Also,
make sure you reference things.
Okay? Make sure that you take
other sources and reference them
in your work. I say three or
four sources of you can have
some informal sources, you can
have more formal sources like
papers, put them into your work.
So it allows you to say why you
think something why you've said
something, typically, you'd
write the 250 words, and then
you go back and put in the
references where you think the
reference backs up what you've
said, it kind of tells people
why you think something with
cold hard facts. Okay? Not just
Oh, I thought of it one day and
so that's, that's why I wrote
it. Okay.
As I said previously in the
welcome. late marks the
university rules apply. So let's
not be thinking that we can do
anything about those late marks.
You know, it all goes into the
university systems and it's
really out of our hands as soon
as those marks come in there.
And the marking rubric, you can
see this online, and it's the
only thing that the TAs get to
look at, including, there's no
hidden way to mark an
assignment, all the market
instructions are available for
you to see and for the TA is to
use to mark with. Okay, so you
need 35% for structure and
argument, knowledge and
understanding 35% and original
thought 30% Okay, so that's
where we're going going for for
this. And, and you can see what
those things mean what it means
to get, you know, a 35% as
opposed to a 5% in structure and
argument on the website. So all
that's open. You can also see it
in your Turn-It-In submission,
but it's all there on the
website. So there's nothing
hidden from you, everything is
explicit. You should be
expecting to get the marking and
feedback within two weeks. So
you can do better in the next
one. So that's why I would
suggest that you kind of stages
these every two weeks do or
maybe or when you get the marks
back do one so that by the by
the time you get to the kind of
third one, you've had the
experience of doing too and you
can hopefully get better and
better marks as you go on. We've
also got real examples from
previous years. These are all
online as well so you can see
what the best look like from
previous years. The thing you
should also know about both the
assignments and the and the
exam. I mark them based on what
I think is appropriate for you,
what's the correct Mark? Okay.
I'm not trying to be harsh I'm
not trying to be easy. I'm
trying to be dispassionate. I'm
trying to make sure that, that
what you're writing here is what
both I would expect. But also
make sure that for other people,
they've, you know, if they've
written a really good, excellent
piece of work, they should be
getting better marks than you,
right? I mean, if you haven't
done that, okay, so I'm not
trying, I'm trying to be as
objective and dispassionate
about this as possible in that
this means that it's possible
for people to get 100% there's
no 95% or 99% because nothing's
perfect or 90%. You can get 100%
in these assignments. Last year
in the exam, I had two people no
had one person who got 100% in
the exam, I could not find a
way. I could not find anything
wrong with it. Okay, they got
100%. Likewise, though, for the
assignments and for the exams
you also can easily get 10's
Okay, it's very difficult unless
you don't turn up to get zero,
it's very difficult if you
submit an assignment that's
actually got words in it, that
makes sense in some way. But
you're going to get more than
zero, but it could happen. So,
just be mindful of the fact that
if you put in a good effort and
you do the work, you'll get the
marks. There's no scaling,
weighting or anything else.
Okay? You get the marks if you
do good work. Okay, and again,
we don't so hopefully, the next
lecture that that you should be
attending certainly in the next
lecture, that I'll be giving the
first lecture for this course is
a face to face lecture now that
will either be via zoom or by
one of your other connection
tools. Or it might even be who
knows, actually co present in a
lecture theatre, you never know!