Hi, I'm Simon and I will
be taking you through
this UX course for this
next semester. So this is
User Experience (UX 36),
the reason why we call it
UX 36 is because it's a
36,000 feet view of the
whole user experience
landscape. The idea is
that you'll get a broad
overview of user
experience, but it won't
be some deep dive because
you'd need a whole course
to do that a whole
programme to do that, in
fact. So, let me welcome
you to this refresh
video. And so you might
be asking, Well, why are
we refreshing? Well,
obviously we're
refreshing for COVID-19
that's why you're
watching a video of this
not me in  person. To
refresh happens for the
user experience course
probably every year with
minor updates Things
change all the time. So
see really good idea to
be able to refresh just
what you're doing. But
it's time for a major
refresh. And it's been
time for a major refresh
for a year or two, I
thought that we could do
some more and add some
more little bits to give
you a good broad
understanding of user
experience and where it
is now. This course was
written six years ago,
things change. And so
some, some big updates
need to be need to be
gone through. And I did
plan to do this on the
sort of next year. So
next September 21-22. But
obviously, with COVID-19,
lockdown as hastened
these changes, so
therefore, it's useful to
just make this a gigantic
update all in one go. So
that's what we're doing.
It's going to be a large
update for the entire
course, for this year, so
you're kind of lucky that
you've got this entire
update all in one go. The
unit's expanded, so it's
become more complete. So
for instance, we're doing
things on digital
phenotyping, which we'll
get to but this wasn't
included in the prior
work, as you'll see,
also, the course itself
will be included as a
GitHub repo. And that's
because a lot of people
say they want to clone
that repo so that they
can use it when they
leave the university so
that the stuff doesn't go
away. And so therefore, I
thought it was best to
kind of make a large
change, you'll still be
doing your assignments,
etc, on Blackboard as
you're used to. But for
this point, the major
meat of the of the of the
update is going to be on
GitHub. It will be on
GitHub Pages for the
website, and then you can
just clone that entire
repo, get everything that
you need to get including
the videos etc, etc. And
there's also been changes
to The definition of what
user experience is, now
we'll get to this in more
detail later on, but it's
really important to
understand that we really
need to make sure that we
understand what UX is,
what user experience is,
what the user experience
is not what the user
experience designer is,
product design, visual
design. So all these
things have kind of
competing, mind space, if
you like, for people in
the area. And so it's a
good thing in some ways,
because nobody really
knows what it is. So we
can kind of make user
experience ours. But also
it can be confusing
unless you explicitly
decide to kind of
understand what UX is
define what UX is for you
personally.
Changes for version four.
So the reason why it's
version four is because
they we've been through a
number of large version
changes and so this is a
this is a main Version
change. But there's also
been lots of little
changes where, you know,
for typos and those kind
of things, which
actually, students send
emails about all the
time, you know, there's a
typo here. Can we change
this? Can we change that
and of course we do over
time. And there's some
reordering of the
material from the last
time because I thought
that it could do with a
refresh with these new
chapters that I'm adding
in these new lectures
that I'm adding some of
some of the material need
to be reordered. Some
changes in emphasis. So
for instance, I used to
do a full scale two hour
lecture on anatomy. And
really, you need to know
about anatomy, you need
to know that these kind
of aspects of the human
body and human behaviour
exist so that you can
write your code for them
better, but you don't
really need to know the
depth. So that's now gone
out and it's no it's kind
of contextual work. We've
got additional sections
on visual design, just
really just really to
give completeness so that
you understand what
again, what that is,
again, that's contextual.
So you want to kind of
look at it, but you don't
really need to have a
deeper understanding of
visual design, because
you're not visual
designers. You know, we
order that service in. So
we don't really need to
think about that. There
are sections, additional
sections on UX design,
what graphic design is
the nature of product
design, these kinds of
things. And I've also
reintegrated the UX
development overview now,
in previous years, I
started off with this
thing called developing
under the umbrella which
was really about how to
develop for user
experience if you were a
developer, but also, how
you might speak to
developers about best
practice for user
experience when it comes
to development. You know,
because it's a complete
system. Obviously, the
Agile process is a
complete system. Remove
that, because I thought,
well, actually, you guys
already are computer
scientists already
software engineers, you
know, you know all this
information. But then I
was asked to bring it
back after a couple of
years. And also, I've
updated it with some
additional aspects of
MVC. So model view
controller architectures,
but more importantly of
micro services
architectures and DevOps.
I decided to bring this
back, because these are
awesome ways of
integrating user
experience into
continuous development
life cycles, and also
into the architectures
that arise from those.
You'll see that in the UX
development part, we're
talking about separation
of concerns, and that
separation of concerns is
really important for us
to to understand. Now.
That's all come back. And
so we'll be going through
that at the very end. But
also we've got some other
aspects on prototyping
because people wanted a
bit more or to understand
a bit more on prototyping
what that is and rapid
application development
what that is and how it
fits in. There's also
some light statistics and
when I say light
statistics, I mean very
light statistics. It's
mostly me ranting. Okay,
so do not worry about
this. It's mostly me
talking a lot about
statistical analysis and
how we should be doing it
and how you should make
sure that you understand
at least some aspects of
stats, even if there are
only a descriptive stats.
And there's a changing
topic title. So some of
the topic titles were a
little bit obscure. So
for instance, you know,
developing the umbrella,
what does that really
mean? So, you know, we've
changed it to make it
more explicit. Obviously,
there's video lectures,
and there's also audio
podcasts. Now, I'm hoping
that we're going to put
these video lectures in
audio podcast, as well as
being in the as well as
been in the GitHub repo,
some way to kind of
integrate them into third
party systems so that you
can actually listen to an
audio podcast on your
normal podcasting system.
You don't have to do
anything different. It
should just integrate
into your life really,
the big change is that
we're going to be
removing the exam as the
key assessment method, or
at least the exam at the
end of the course that
you do in a normal exam
setting what we all think
of as an exam. Okay, so
that's the main thing
that that kind of changes
here.
And what we're going to
have and we'll get to
this in the welcome talk
that I'll be giving
shortly, when we get to
is a an exam that is kind
of more blended into the
course. So we've we've
moved, we used to have
three assignments now we
have one formative
assignment, two summative
assignments, those are
open book, you get the
assignment beforehand,
everything's good. We
then we then in the exam
used to have some
multiple choice
questions, and we also
used to have some kind of
shorter answer type
questions. These have
been taken from the old
exam, put together into
one assessment. And
that's also an assessment
now, that gets delivered
later on in the year. And
it comes from a question
bank. So you'll need to
know everything,
everybody will be
delivered a different
kind of exam a different
set of questions, even
though they're all
multiple choice, you'll
get a random set from the
question bank and there's
about 150 questions in
the question bank, if
you've managed to
memorise them all great,
but the reality is that
that's unlikely; so
you'll still need to have
some understanding of the
user experience behind
it. Then we've also got a
larger assignment type of
sessional, if you like,
exam, whereby you're
doing it remotely, you're
doing it asynchronously,
you'll have a set period
of time to do that in.
But again, the questions
are all different, you'll
be presented with
different questions.
So this update, as I say,
is a major update that
COVID-19 forced. It's
been put off because it
was a large amount of
work and I wanted to do
this in a graduated step,
but because we're all you
know, sitting around in
our homes in lockdown,
then I've got quite a lot
of time now to do this.
Now, of course, I'm not
really in a swanky
lecture theatre come
conference room, I'm here
in the front room of my
house, it's the front box
bedroom trying to do this
in front of a green
screen. It's just me in
front of a green screen.
There's nothing to see
here. Okay, let's get
back to the lecture.
So the assignments and
testing have changed. And
reality is that even
though we've been forced
to make these changes by
the by the situation,
it's better, that better.
They're the kind of
assignments and testing
that I've wanted to do
for a long time but
couldn't get the approval
for now all bets are off,
we've suddenly got the
got what we need. So I'm
really pleased that that
we've been able to get
these assignments and
testing changes through.
And they're just the kind
of things we wanted. So
this is going to be
really good. Now, we
won't be physically co
present, so we won't be
in the same room. I
imagine we wouldn't be
anywhere at this point in
the same room. But we'll
have two different
things. We'll have
asynchronous work, and
we'll have synchronous
work. So asynchronous
means that it's this kind
of thing, video lectures.
They'll also be
asynchronous discussion
topics via discord
probably. So you will
leave questions that you
need answering etc. and I
will answer them over the
period of week but we
won't be on the platform
probably at the same
time. And then we'll have
synchronous sort of
lectures. So those
synchronous lectures will
probably be occurring
about once a week.
They'll be us via zoom or
something like this.
We'll be going through
example, But also
there'll be discussion
there. And we'll see why
you can't skip these or
that you can't get good
marks if you do skip
them. So just think about
that. And these will be
live, and they'll be face
to face and there won't
be recorded because
they're more about you
guys participating if you
really don't come then
the core components of
the of the work, which is
already pre recorded,
like this, should be fine
for you to understand
what's happening.
So there'll be a
synchronous open surgery
for one hour a week, it
could be via zoom. It
will be once a week, as I
say, and it means that we
can actually chat face to
face. Now, you won't need
to be there if you don't
want to be simply. You
don't need to be at the
surgery. That's just a
spot where if you feel
that you need some
feedback, you need
something that's
synchronous, something
that is where we're
talking to Together, then
that's fine, you can turn
up to that. But it's you
don't have to go there.
It's really just for
problems or to go through
examples or if there's
something you didn't
quite understand. Then we
can go and talk about it
on the on that zoom call,
and I'll be there you
just, you'll get the code
sign-in when you like it
anytime you write within
that one hour, but it
will finish on the hour,
so you know, you need to
come beforehand. Don't
leave it till the very
last moment.
Okay, so we're done.
You'll notice that
there's a transcription
available with this
video, the transcription
has been made also into
subtitles, and there'll
be a transcript and
subtitles for every video
that you see. So make
sure if you need those
subtitles, make sure that
you switch them on in
your particular video
viewer. Okay, so, have a
good rest of your week,
and we'll see you in the
next one.